<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A word in the behalf of the King that he may see who they are that honour all men, and love the brother-hood, and honour the King ...</title>
            <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 27 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A40326</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">10329677</idno>
  <idno type="VID">44869</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240948010</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing F1993</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R28017</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">10329677</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A40326)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 44869)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1384:34)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A word in the behalf of the King that he may see who they are that honour all men, and love the brother-hood, and honour the King ...</title>
                  <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>15 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Robert Wilson,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1660.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed: G.F.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Harvard University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Conduct of life.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Society of Friends --  Apologetic works.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>John Latta </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:44869:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:44869:1"/>
            <head>A WORD In the behalf of the KING,</head>
            <p>That he may see who they are that Honour all men, and Love the Brother-hood, that Fear God, and Honour the King, according as it is written in the Scriptures of Truth, see 1 <hi>Pet.</hi> 2.17. Which is a beesom to sweep away all sin and wickednesse which dishonours the King and the Nation.</p>
            <p>For who live in all manner of sin and wickednesse, Drunkennesse, Oaths, and Uncleannesse, and Ungod<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>linesse, these live out of Gods fear, so cannot Honour the King.</p>
            <p>But they that depart from all manner of sin, ungodliness, unrighteousness, uncleanness, filthiness, swearing, are them that Fear God, and Honour the King; And also how that Christ ends the <hi>Jews</hi> Law, by which they were to kill about Religion such as were contrary-minded, and he never gave out any since to do so, but to love enemies; But all Laws by which the Christians do now persecute, are gotten up in the Apostacy since the dayes of the Apostles; and though the <hi>Jews</hi> and <hi>Gentiles</hi> were to hate Enemies, and to kill them; yet you may see that Christ's Command and Doctrine was to love Enemies, and they that do so are the true Christians.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Robert Wilson,</hi> at the Sign of the <hi>Black spread-Eagle</hi> and <hi>Windmill</hi> in <hi>Martins Le-Grand,</hi> 1660.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="treatise">
            <pb facs="tcp:44869:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:44869:2"/>
            <p>LEt all people consider what <hi>they do,</hi> and what <hi>they say,</hi> and <hi>practice;</hi> who say they arc Christians (and go under that name) and bring <hi>Peters</hi> words, 1 <hi>Pet.</hi> 2.17. Honour all men, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Mark! that is a large word, for if they honoured <hi>all men,</hi> then they would not hurt <hi>any man,</hi> but <hi>love</hi> all men, and have all men <hi>in esteem,</hi> and if they esteemed a man, they would never hurt him; and if they esteemed all men, and ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noured them, then they would hurt no man. So if they did but practice that which they say, here would be no strife in Christendom; Nor would there be strife with any men, nor hatred of any man, nor violence, nor stri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king any man, for he honoured him, and had him in e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>steem, and he that honoured him loved him.</p>
            <p>Now he that doth not honour all men, nor doth not love all men, nor hath not all men in esteem, (though he may say these words of the Apostle, yet he is out of the Doctrine of the Apostle and practice) he is in the nature of a Jew, or a Heathen, that hates, and dishonours, slanders, back-bites, and envies, and doth violence to men, doth not honour them, nor hath them not in e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>steem, nor doth not love them. So look what derision, scorn, maliciousnesse, and what envy men live in, abu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sing one another, and wronging one another, yet would not these be called Christians? Doth these honour all men? Do these love all men, even their Enemies? Have these all men in esteem, that will strike, and fight, and shed mens bloud? Are these such as keep Christs com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands, who saith, <hi>Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, with all thy mind, with all thy soul, and with all thy strength, and thou shalt love thy neighbour as thy self,
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:44869:3"/>Luke</hi> 10.27. and again he saith, <hi>all things whatsoever ye would that <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> should do unto you, do ye the same unto them, for that is <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Law and the Prophets, Luke</hi> 6.31. now he that loves his neighbour as himself, he will not hurt him; and he that wrongeth or deceiveth his neighbour, or stri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keth, or abuseth, or sheds another mans bloud, he would not have the same done unto himself by another, and so such a one is out of Christs doctrine, and a transgressor of the Law and the Prophets: But now is it not so, that many have <hi>cloaths in esteem,</hi> and <hi>riches in esteem,</hi> and so <hi>admire</hi> mens persons because of advantage, and so be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come respectors of mens persons, and do not <hi>honour</hi> all men, but <hi>disesteem</hi> them that have <hi>not fine cloaths,</hi> and <hi>gay apparel,</hi> and <hi>Riches,</hi> and esteem them that have; and so <hi>honour</hi> the one, and <hi>dishonour</hi> the other; now this is re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>specting of persons, and not to honour all men, as the Apostle <hi>James</hi> speaks of, who saith, <hi>Jam.</hi> 2.12. <hi>My Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren, have not the Faith of our Lord Jesus Christ the Lord of glory with respect of persons: For if there come a man with</hi> a gold ring, and goodly apparel, <hi>and there come in also a poor man</hi> in vile raiment, <hi>and ye have respect to him that weareth</hi> the gay cloathing, <hi>and say unto him</hi> sit thou here in a good place, <hi>and say to the poor man</hi> stand thou there, or sit here <hi>under my foot-stool;</hi> now this is the respecter of persons, who hath not the faith of our Lord Jesus Christ, and not the honourer of all men, And so there is the Sectary; but who honours all men, they are no Sectaries, but are out of them all.</p>
            <p n="2">2. The second thing is this, <hi>love the brother-hood,</hi> and <hi>love enemies;</hi> now here is the two things, to love ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies, <hi>it is not to kill them,</hi> and <hi>to destroy them,</hi> but to overcome them <hi>with the good;</hi> Now the Enemies are Sons of <hi>Adam,</hi> in whom the Enmity is, and the sins
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:44869:3"/>of the flesh, who be strangers from the life of God, and the Covenant of promise and Son-ship, in which is the Brother-hood.</p>
            <p>And so they that be in the love of God (which is to the World) who would have them to be saved, and to know his mind, and his Salvation; now if they would have all men to be saved, they would not have them de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stroyed, neither destroy them: Let them be <hi>Hypocrites,</hi> let them be <hi>Blasphemers,</hi> let them be <hi>Schismaticks,</hi> or <hi>He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reticks,</hi> or <hi>Phanaticks,</hi> let them be what they will, he would have them to be saved. And the patience, and long-suffering of God, is great Salvation; <hi>Paul</hi> and <hi>David</hi> who were great transgressors did witness it. But the unpatient <hi>(which are the tares)</hi> they destroy the <hi>Saints,</hi> and pluck up <hi>the wheat for tears,</hi> as <hi>Blasphemers</hi> and <hi>Hereticks.</hi> But these have not the Spirit of Christ guiding of them, and such cannot love Enemies, for they that hate Enemies, are out of the Commands of Christ, and out of his Spirit and mind, who persecute a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout Religion, and Church-worship, but do not love Enemies; neither are they in the Brotherly fellowship, nor in the Spirit and power of God that goes over all transgression, that was before it was; and so they that hate Enemies have not <hi>all men</hi> in esteem, (mark, <hi>all men</hi>) these are not in the Brotherly fellow-ship, nor do not love Brother-hood, but are respectors of persons, that do not honour all men, and love Enemies, but are in <hi>hatred,</hi> and <hi>envy,</hi> and <hi>fury,</hi> and <hi>rage,</hi> and <hi>madnesse</hi> (not in the love and meekness) and <hi>that is the Phanaticks Spirit,</hi> that loves not enemies.</p>
            <p n="3">3. Thirdly, <hi>fear God and honour the King;</hi> So mark, they that fear God, honours the King, and to fear God is to depart from sin, and evil (and that keeps the
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:44869:4"/>clean heart) which is the beginning of wisdome. Now such as fear not God, honour not the King, and such as depart not from sin and evil, fear not God, and they ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour not the King.</p>
            <p>It may be they may talk of him with the lips, and bow the knee, put off the Hat, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> But that is not the honour; for they that live not in the fear of God do not honour the King. Drunkards, and swearers and cursers you fear not God, therefore you honour not the King; for the Scripture saith <hi>ye shall not swear</hi> nor <hi>curse,</hi> as <hi>Paul</hi> saith to the <hi>Galatians,</hi> and as Christ saith, 5. <hi>Mat.</hi> And <hi>James</hi> saith 5. <hi>Jam.</hi> And all ye who live <hi>in Adultery, Fornication, Ʋncleanness, Idolatry, Whoredome, Laciviousness, Effeminateness, Pleasures, Gameing, Sporting, Past-time,</hi> which stirs up <hi>vain</hi> and <hi>idle words</hi> (for which ye must give an account) and <hi>vain actions,</hi> and taking <hi>Gods Name in vain,</hi> ye fear not God that do so; there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore ye honour not the King, but do dishonour him, and this Nation, and his Government, and his Kingdome; <hi>For Righteousness exalteth a Nation, but sin is a reproach to any People</hi> saith Solomon, And saith the Apostle, <hi>this know ye, that no whore monger, nor unclean Person, or cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tous man who is an Idolatar hath any Inheritance in the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dome of Christ or of God,</hi> 5. <hi>Gal.</hi> 5.</p>
            <p>And all ye <hi>Couzeners, Cheaters, Defrauders, Dissemblers, Lyars, Back-biters, Slanderers, False Accusers, Envious,</hi> and <hi>Malitious persons, Murtherers, Plotters, Fighters, Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rellers, Brawlers, Scoulders, Tumultuousones, Ryoters, Ambitious, Proud, Heady, High-minded, Vain-glorious, Perverse, VVicked</hi> and <hi>VVilful-men,</hi> you live not in Gods fear, therefore you cannot honour the King; for they who honour the King, must fear God, as ye may read 1 <hi>Pet</hi> 2.17. <hi>All Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proachers, Scoffers, Scorners, Despisers,</hi> and <hi>Mockers, and
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:44869:4"/>such as give Nick-names, to one another, and foolish jesters, and vain and corrupt and filthy talkers, who vomit out your own shame by your corrupt Communication, you fear not God, therefore you do not honour the King in your hearts;</hi> You must come to the witness of God in your selves all of you, which lets you see sin and evil, and depart from it, which is the fear of God to depart from sin and evil, and then ye come to honour the King as ye live in Gods fear and no otherwise.</p>
            <p>And all ye <hi>who are Earthly minded</hi> and live <hi>in Oppression, Extortion, grinding the face of the poor,</hi> in <hi>Covetousness</hi> which is <hi>Idolatry,</hi> and <hi>Rebellion</hi> against God, which is as the sin of <hi>witch-craft,</hi> and <hi>Stubbornness</hi> which is <hi>iniquity,</hi> and say you shall have peace, though ye walk in the stubbernness of your hearts, and regard not the Lord, <hi>ye fear not God, neither do ye honour the King.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And all you <hi>Ʋnsober, Ʋntemperate, Ʋnmodest, Ʋngra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions,</hi> who chuse <hi>vice</hi> rather <hi>than vertue</hi> and <hi>piety,</hi> you fear not <hi>God,</hi> but cast <hi>his Law</hi> and <hi>his fear</hi> behind your backs; Therefore you honour not the King, for ye are to be in <hi>the fear of God,</hi> before <hi>you honour the King.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>So never profess that ye are honourers of the King, who do not live in the fear of God, and never profess that ye are fearing God and honouring of the King, while ye are <hi>Cursing, Swearing Damning, Roaring, Drinking healths,</hi> and <hi>Spoyling</hi> and <hi>Mis-spending, Consuming,</hi> and <hi>Destroying</hi> the <hi>Creatures, and drinking in, and vomitting up again</hi> all that be there <hi>(and are so doing)</hi> fear not God, and so they do not honour the King, (this is not for the Kings health, nor this is not for the Kings honour;) But as I said before, such dishonour him.</p>
            <p>And all that follow <hi>the vain fashons of this world,</hi> that live in the <hi>lusts of the flesh,</hi> the lust of <hi>the eye,</hi> and the
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:44869:5"/>
               <hi>pride of life,</hi> which is not of God the Father but of the World, these fear not God, so they honour not the King.</p>
            <p>And all <hi>Thieves, Robbers, Man-slayers, Plotters</hi> to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stroy mens persons, lives and estates, to bring men into poverty and to undoe one another; these live not in the fear of God, which is <hi>to love enemies, and to do good for evil;</hi> and these honour not all men, these love not the Brotherhood, these cannot honour the King, that live not in Gods feare.</p>
            <p>All they <hi>that make discord,</hi> and <hi>Strife</hi> and <hi>dissention amongst people</hi> by <hi>lyes,</hi> and <hi>false reports,</hi> and dissemble to get gain, and lay snares for the Righteous, and betray the innocent to get gain and advantage to themselves, by telling lyes of some to others, <hi>These fear not God, these do not honour the King.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And all <hi>who envy</hi> one another about <hi>their fashons,</hi> and <hi>dyet,</hi> because they have not means to maintain it, <hi>as high</hi> as <hi>others</hi> (though they would be in the same fashion, &amp; live as high as others) but their estates will not maintain it. And therefore they envy all others who have Estates, &amp; can maintain it. And likewise they that have Estates to maintain their fashons, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> They envy others that would be there, and do as they do, but have not where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withal to maintain it; And so these do not esteem all men, nor love Brotherhood, nor fear God, nor honour the King, that have these evils undeparted from; for they that go into evil, and live in evil or in any manner of sin and wickedness do not fear God, but they fear God <hi>that depart from sin and evil,</hi> and such are they that honour all men and love the Brother-hood, who depart from sin, and <hi>these are they that honour the King.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But now <hi>Cursers Swearers, Covenant-breakers, Perjured Persons</hi> who will <hi>Swear</hi> and <hi>break Oaths</hi> and <hi>forswear,</hi> make <hi>Covenant</hi>
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:44869:5"/>and <hi>Vows,</hi> and <hi>promises,</hi> and <hi>Protestatious,</hi> and <hi>Leagues,</hi> and <hi>break them,</hi> such fear not God, nor honour the King.</p>
            <p>And such <hi>as will fight,</hi> and <hi>kill,</hi> and <hi>destroy</hi> for a mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sel of bread, or a mess of pottage, are prophane as <hi>Esau</hi> was; These are men, <hi>without natural affection, lovers of themselves, and lovers of pleasures more then lovers of God, Boasters, proud, blasphemers, disobedient to parents, unthankful, unholy, truce-breakers, incontinent, fierce, dispisers of them that are good, Traytors, and men of Corrupt minds, and to every good work are reprobates</hi> These do not fear God, neither can these honour the King, nor the Kingdome nor Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion wherein they live.</p>
            <p>All that follow <hi>Gluttony, Excess</hi> and <hi>Ryot,</hi> who <hi>Eat</hi> and <hi>drink,</hi> and <hi>rise up to play, Feasting, Banquetting, Stage-playings, Bear-beatings, Cock-fightings, Horse-racings, Hunt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings, Hawkings, Dancings, Chamberings, Wantonness,</hi> spend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing their times <hi>after the lusts and pleasures of the world,</hi> which perish with the using; these fear not God, these are not like to honour the King, that destroy the Crea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures, upon their lusts and vain pleasures.</p>
            <p>Therefore tremble before the Lord God, ye that fear not his Name, but live in <hi>Sin</hi> and <hi>VVickedness, Enviousness, Malitiousness, Strife, Bitterness, VVrath, Anger,</hi> and <hi>Cla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mour,</hi> and <hi>evil Speaking, Lyeing, False accusing, Persecuting</hi> the <hi>Innocent,</hi> live in <hi>Drunkenness, Bloody-mindedness, Hate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful,</hi> and <hi>hating one another, Desperateness, Rash, Hasty, Froward, Ʋnruly, Disorderly, Fierce, Rebellious, Ʋnmerciful, Cruel, Hard-hearted, Fierce, Dispisers, VVrathful, Obstinate, Wilful, Stubborn,</hi> full <hi>of threatnings, Revilings, haters of God;</hi> Ye love <hi>not enemies,</hi> ye honour <hi>not all men,</hi> ye do <hi>not love the Brother-hood,</hi> ye do <hi>not depart from sin</hi> and <hi>evil,</hi> ye do <hi>not fear God,</hi> nor is it like <hi>that ye should honour the King.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And therefore all people from the highest to the
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:44869:6"/>lowest; it is a warning; <hi>to you</hi> all <hi>to depart from sin and all manner of evil whatsoever.</hi> Ye that live <hi>in Adultery, Idolatry, Fornication, Ʋncleanness, Whore do me, Cursing, Swearing, Drunkenness, Lying, Sporting,</hi> and <hi>Pleasures,</hi> and <hi>in Couzening, Cheating, Deceiving,</hi> and <hi>Defrauding one another, Dissembling, Reproaching, Persecuting</hi> one another <hi>with tongue,</hi> or <hi>hand, Back-biting,</hi> or <hi>Slandering,</hi> or <hi>false-accusing</hi> one another, <hi>Rage, Malice</hi> and <hi>Hatred,</hi> and <hi>En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vying</hi> one another; fear God and depart from these things, and come into the <hi>Chastness</hi> and <hi>Temperance</hi> and <hi>Sobriety,</hi> and <hi>Truth,</hi> and <hi>Righteousness,</hi> and <hi>meekness,</hi> and <hi>Lowliness</hi> of mind, out of the high-mindedness, and to love the Brother-hood, honour all men, fear God, and then you honour the King.</p>
            <p>For as ye live <hi>in sin</hi> and <hi>evil,</hi> ye honour <hi>not all men,</hi> ye love <hi>not the Brother-hood,</hi> ye fear <hi>not God,</hi> ye honour <hi>not the King;</hi> That is the word of the Lord God to you all, <hi>ye dishonour men,</hi> ye <hi>dishonour the Brother hood,</hi> ye <hi>dishonour the King,</hi> ye cast <hi>the fear of God</hi> behind <hi>your backs</hi> (and his Law also) who live in sin and evil, though ye prate never so much <hi>of your honouring the King,</hi> we will never believe you, <hi>that you honour him while ye live in sin,</hi> for that is it which is <hi>to his dishonour</hi> and <hi>reproach,</hi> and will bring the Judgements of God upon the Land.</p>
            <p>So while ye <hi>live</hi> in the <hi>wrath,</hi> and <hi>revenge, Swearing, Cursing, Blaspheming the Name of God, and taking it in vain,</hi> and <hi>professing him in words,</hi> but <hi>in works denying of him,</hi> living in <hi>Lying, Deceit,</hi> and <hi>Hypocrisie,</hi> and <hi>Dissimulation,</hi> in <hi>Ʋnrighteousnesse, Injustice,</hi> and <hi>Iniquity,</hi> in <hi>Pride, Idle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesse,</hi> and <hi>fulnesse of bread,</hi> in <hi>Drunkennesse, Riotousnesse,</hi> and <hi>vain pleasures</hi> and <hi>delights</hi> (which causeth ye to for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>get God) and all manner of <hi>Conzening, Cheating, Deceit, Defrauding, Puft up, Heady, High-minded, Ambitious,</hi> and
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:44869:6"/>
               <hi>overreaching</hi> one another in bargaining, to overthrowone another to make your selves rich; We do say, and know, and believe that you neither <hi>fear God,</hi> nor <hi>honour the King,</hi> nor <hi>love Enemies,</hi> nor <hi>love the Brother-hood,</hi> nor <hi>ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour all men,</hi> who are so wicked, and malicious, and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vious against men.</p>
            <p>And all <hi>that are Persecutors</hi> about <hi>Religion, Church-wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ship, Ordinances, Ministers Maintenance,</hi> and their <hi>Tradi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions,</hi> which the Apostles never did so in the Primitive times, neither did Christ ever give any such Command; these fear <hi>not God</hi> that do so, neither do they honour <hi>all men</hi> that do persecute them, (about <hi>Religion</hi> and <hi>Worship,</hi> and cast them into prison) nor <hi>love Enemies,</hi> nor <hi>love Brother-hood,</hi> nor <hi>fear God,</hi> nor <hi>Christ,</hi> nor <hi>honour the King;</hi> for Christ gave them no such command, as ye may read in the Scriptures of truth.</p>
            <p>Fifthly, and all them that persecute people about <hi>observing of dayes,</hi> and not observing <hi>of dayes, meats,</hi> and <hi>drinks,</hi> which stands in the will-worship, as the Apostle speaks of, 2. <hi>Col.</hi> who neglect the body; and the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of Heaven <hi>stands not in such things,</hi> but <hi>righteousness,</hi> and <hi>peace,</hi> and <hi>joy in the Holy Ghost;</hi> And they that do so, do contrary to the Apostle, who said, <hi>Let every man be fully perswaded in his own mind,</hi> (<hi>Rom.</hi> 14.) brings people from waiting to be satisfied in their own minds, that per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>secutes them, and compels them to observe dayes, and times, and months, and years; These love not Brother-hood, nor honour not all men, nor fear not God, nor Christ, nor honour not the King; For that which keeps in the honour <hi>of the King;</hi> keeps <hi>in Righteousnesse,</hi> keeps <hi>in Truth,</hi> keeps <hi>in Justice</hi> which establisheth a Kingdom, and keeps <hi>in the Kingdom of God</hi> which stands not in meats and drinks, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="12" facs="tcp:44869:7"/>
            <p> Sixthly, and all who teach <hi>for filthy lucre, for hire,</hi> and for <hi>the love of money,</hi> such serve not the Lord Jesus Christ but their own bellies; And all who judge for gifts and rewards, and oppresse the poor, and do not equal justice to all, and minister freely, as Christ commanded (who have received freely) these fear not God, nor regard not the Scriptures of truth, nor honour the King, who is to keep all in Truth, Righteousnesse, and Justice.</p>
            <p>Seventhly, and all who <hi>get a form of godlinesse,</hi> the Scripture of truth (which was given forth from them who were in the Spirit of truth) and yet prison, and persecute such as are in the same Spirit as they were in that gave it forth; These neither regard God, nor his fear, nor truth, justice, nor equity; So these cannot honour the King, but such who honour the King, must be <hi>Temperate, Moderate, Sober, Patient, Meek, Mild, Gentle, Loving, do Equally, Justly, Righteously, be Holy, Godly, True,</hi> and <hi>Faithful, Peaceable, Merciful,</hi> and <hi>Humble;</hi> for <hi>Humility</hi> is that which goes before the <hi>Honour,</hi> and these are the fruits of them <hi>that fear God,</hi> and <hi>honour the King,</hi> and <hi>love the Brother-hood,</hi> and <hi>honour all men,</hi> 1 <hi>Pet.</hi> 2.17.</p>
            <p>And the fruits of them that fear not God, and do not honour the King, nor love the Brother-hood, nor honour all men, (though they pretend to do it) are such as these, <hi>viz. Cursing, Swearing, Drunkennesse, Whordome, Lying, Murder, Plotting, Killing, Fighting, Theft, Adultery, Fornication, Lasciviousnesse, Pride, Envy, Hatred, Malice, Cruelty, Oppression, Ʋnmercifulnesse, Idolatry, Covetousnesse, Inordinate Affections, Lust, Voluptuousnesse, Ʋnsatiablenesse, Incorrigablenesse, Impenitency, Ʋnbelief, Ʋncharitablenesse, Ʋnthankfulnesse, Hardnesse of Heart, Enmity, Strife, Emula<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, Discord, Persecution,</hi> and <hi>haling</hi> men without cause,
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:44869:7"/>and laying snares for the Innocent.</p>
            <p>Never did any kill about Religion but the Heathen, and <hi>Cain,</hi> and the Jews, who had a Law from God to kill and put to death such as drew them from their God, by which Law they were to receive a punishment according to their transgression, whipt, or stoned, or run through; therefore did the Jews think they did God good service, by killing such as were contrary minded to them, in that they did obey the Law. Therefore under this pretence they did kill the Saints, the Christians in the Primitive times, for they were to love their Brethren, and to hate their Enemies; for they were their Enemies, the Heathen, and Gentiles, and such as set up a strange God among them. Therefore the Christians (who own Christ, which ends this Law, and the Jews types, and figures, and sha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dows held up by it) were to love Enemies; and this was the difference whereby they differed from the Pharisees, that were to hate Enemies, &amp; the Christians were to love them; for the time hath been saith Christ, <hi>an eye for an eye, a tooth for a tooth,</hi> but saith he now, <hi>He that smiteth thee on the one cheek, turn to him the other, and resist not evil, but love your Enemies;</hi> Now the Jews who hated Enemies, their weapons <hi>were carnal,</hi> but they that love enemies (the Christians) their weapons were and are spiritual; So Christ ends that Law of the Jews, which they thought they did God good service by, when they put to death them that were contrary minded to them; for they could not love Enemies that killed them, nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther can they that love Enemies now kill them; for they love them that preserve them, and do not kill them; for Christ who endeth the Prophets (when his Disciples would have had fire to come down from Heaven, as the Prophet had) rebuked them, and told them <hi>they knew
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:44869:8"/>not what Spirit they were of,</hi> and said <hi>he came not to destroy mens lives, but to save them.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And so never did Christ nor the Apostles set up any Law or Commandment <hi>to imprison,</hi> or <hi>persecute</hi> any <hi>Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren, or enemies,</hi> but love, for God loved the world; and so they that love the Brother-hood, and honour all men, that have all men in esteem, they cannot hurt any man upon the Earth, that oweth nothing to any man <hi>but love,</hi> that is the debt which must be paid, for <hi>Love</hi> envies not, and he <hi>that envies</hi> is out <hi>of Love,</hi> and not a Child <hi>of God,</hi> but <hi>of Cain,</hi> and so a <hi>vagabond.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now all Christendom do professe Christ and God in words (but are out of the life, and out of the power) who fall into differences and strife about <hi>earthly things,</hi> and <hi>inventions,</hi> as dayes, meats, and their own <hi>traditions,</hi> which the Kingdom of God stands not in, but <hi>in Power, in Righteousnesse,</hi> and <hi>joy in the Holy Ghost;</hi> But now since the dayes of Christ and the Apostles in the Primitive times, they have made Laws to persecute one another; who have lost <hi>Brother-hood,</hi> honouring <hi>all men,</hi> which if they were in the Kingdom which stands in power (and not in <hi>meats</hi> and <hi>drinks,</hi> or <hi>dayes,</hi> or <hi>outward things</hi>) but in righteousnesse, peace, and joy in the Holy Ghost, then they would feel the law of Love, the Law of the Spirit of life, and to be made free from the Law of sin and death. But they that fall out <hi>about dayes,</hi> and <hi>meats,</hi> and <hi>drinks,</hi> and <hi>inventions,</hi> and their own <hi>traditions</hi> be out of the Kingdom of God, and out of the Brotherly love, not esteeming all men, not fearing God, And they that do so, are contrary to Christ and the Apostles in the Primi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tive times.</p>
            <p>So they do not God good service that do persecute about Religion now, and about the Church worship,
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:44869:8"/>for Christ commands them to love Enemies, who ended the Jews Law, that did persecute the Gentiles, and such among themselves as did draw from the Law of <hi>God;</hi> And he broke down the partition-wall which was be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween Jew and Gentile, who slew the enmity, and so of twain made one new man, and thereby came the love to Enemies.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>G. F.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>